Nathalie McCubbin

UI & Visual Designer

nathalie.mccubbin@gmail.com www.behance.net/nathalimccubb Berlin, Germany

PROFILE

UI and visual designer with a background in fashion design. Enthusiastic in achieving stimulating design solutions that solve pain points and enhance a positive and meaningful user experience. Proficient in designing products for a variety of customer groups worldwide.

SKILLS

Software

- Sketch
- · Adobe XD
- Figma
- Invision
- Illustrator
- Procreate
- Photoshop

Design

- · User Interface
- Branding
- · Visual Design
- Illustration
- User Personas
- Usability Analysis
- · User Research
- Wireframing
- Prototyping

EDUCATION

UI Design Certificate 2021 | CareerFoundry

Bachelor of Arts (Hons) in Fashion 2015 | Kingston University, London

LANGUAGES

English - Native/Bilingual German - Native/Bilingual

WORK EXPERIENCE

UI & Visual Designer | Recipe

Jan 2021 - Present | Berlin, Germany

- · Leading the directions for creating web applications
- Researching UI trends, creating mood boards, collaborating with the content director and project managers, performing usability testing
- · Creating branding, style guides and MVPs

Concept Designer | Roeckl Handschuhe & Accessoires

May 2019 - Nov 2019 | Munich, Germany

- Developed on-trend designs for a younger demographic
- Created concepts and mood boards as creative guidelines, integrated vegan leathers and optional fabrics, designed new handbags and small leather goods, worked closely with the marketing and e-commerce department
- Successfully launched first vegan leather articles and enhanced a cohesive range across product groups, established a modern direction to attract a younger market

Senior Fashion Designer | H&M

June 2017 - Oct 2018 | Stockholm, Sweden

- Built more sustainable collections for the kids and youth sector sold on a global scale
- Managed a team of 6, developed and tested alternative materials to increase sustainability, created 14 collections a year following the latest trends and concept guidelines
- Implemented higher usage of recycled materials, successfully launched the first recycled unisex jersey collection for kids

Junior Fashion Designer | H&M

Nov 2015 - May 2017 | Stockholm, Sweden

- Managed nightwear products in coordination with the senior designer
- Worked with the print designer and buyer to visualize the final product, and meet deadlines, presented design ideas to the creative team
- Increased sales of nightwear products ultimately resulting in the creation of the nightwear product team

Designer & Illustrator | Dar Leone

Nov 2012 - May 2015 | London, UK

- · Designed prints and products for soft furnishing
- Forecasted and interpreted interior design trends as appropriate to the brand and for the customer base
- · Increased sales B2B and B2C